A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, M-R FA393
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Marshall, John
  - Trip to Paris, 1951 June 16-July 12; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 71 pages (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 756, Box 298)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. He attends the Unesco General Conference, visits England and explores Rockefeller Foundation interests in Near East studies.
    Diaries
  - 1951 October 16-December 29, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 215 pages (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 960, Box 298)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. He attends various conferences including Seminar in Literary Criticism; the annual meeting of the National Theater Conference and American Historical Association meetings.
    History; Education; Theater; Humanities; Diaries; Drama; United States
  - 1952 January 4-March 16, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 185 pages (Reel M Mar 8, Frame 1, Box 298)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to aid humanistic studies which have a direct relevance to contemporary life, support activities designed to interpret contemporary cultures and encourage study of foreign languages as an aid to eliminate barriers to international cooperation. Marshall attends the Fourth Annual Near East Conference and the U.S. National Conference for Unesco. He also discusses various avenues in which Rockefeller Foundation Humanities Arabic Program could go.
    Libraries; Linguistics; Language and languages; Lebanon; United States; Middle East; Syria; Education; England; Egypt; Iraq; Humanities; Diaries
  - Near East Trip, 1952; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John (Reel M Mar 8, Frame 92)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to aid humanistic studies which have a direct relevance to contemporary life, support activities designed to interpret contemporary cultures and encourage study of foreign languages as an aid to eliminate barriers to international cooperation. Marshall travels to the Near East continues and he attends the Fourth Annual Near East Conference at Princeton University.
  - 1952 March 9-May 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 152 pages (Box 299, Reel M Mar 8, Frame 186)
    Diaries; Cultural history; United States; Turkey; Lebanon; Theater; Humanities; Language and languages; Education; France; Drama
  - 1952 June 3-September 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 163 pages (Box 299, Box 338, Frame 338)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. He attends a conference on television and discusses with the Department of State and Library of Congress an Islamic Colloquim.
    Television; Libraries; Islamic studies; Humanities; Education; Diaries; United States
  - 1952 October 1-November 28, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 202 pages (Reel M Mar 8, Frame 503, Box 299)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. He visits Puerto Rico to survey the proposal of developing university programs, and visits Louisville, Kentucky to survey University of Louisville's School of Music. Marshall attends the Princeton Seminar in Literary Criticism and the Unesco General Conference.
    Humanities; Libraries; Middle East; Music; Puerto Rico; Theater; United States; Germany; France; Education; Drama; Diaries; Arts
  - Trip to Paris, 1952 December 1-30; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 121 pages (Box 299, Reel M Mar 8, Frame 709)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The diary documents his trip to Paris to attend the Unesco Conference.
    Cultural history; France; Humanities; Social sciences; Theater; United States
  - 1953 January 2-March 20, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 213 pages (Reel M Mar 8, Frame 830, Box 299)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts. Marshall takes a trip to the Near East to survey Arab studies, Language and translation projects. The diary includes reports on Egypt and Iraq's current political climate.
    Humanities; Iraq; England; History; Egypt; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Drama; Education; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Translations; Diaries; Music; United States; Linguistics; Libraries; Lebanon; Language and languages
  - Trip to the Near East, 1953 February 15-March 20; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 181 pages (Box 299, Reel M Mar 8, Frame 925)
  - 1953 March 20-May 28, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 8, Frame 1,043, Box 299)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts. Marshall continues his travels in the Near East, attends Bhamdoum Meetings and the Fifth Annual Near East Conference at Princeton University.
    Lebanon; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Humanities; Language and languages; United States; Translations; Turkey; Education; American literature
  - Trip to the Near East, March 20-April 12, 1953; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 8, Frame 1,044, Box 299)
  - 1953 June 1-September 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 187 pages (Box 300, Reel M Mar 9, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The diary documents the Princeton University Colloquium on Islamic Culture.
    Islamic studies; Music; Education; Humanities; Diaries; United States; Television; Theater
  - 1953 October 1-December 1, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 150 pages (Reel M Mar 9, Frame 188, Box 300)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts.
    Diaries; United States; Humanities; Education
  - 1954 January 1-March 25, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 147 pages (Box 300, Reel M Mar 9, Frame 338)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts. The diary details the Museum of Modern Art Film Library special project and includes a comparison of successive budgets for the American Shakespeare Festival Theatre and Academy.
    Arts; Education; Dance; Ballet; Motion pictures; Libraries; Diaries; Humanities; Film; United States; Theater; Museums
  - 1954 March 16-July 29, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 238 pages (Reel M Mar 9, Frame 485, Box 300)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts. Marshall takes a trip to the Near East from 16 March to 4 April, 1954 to survey higher education in the Near East, American studies abroad and attend a conference in Cairo, Egypt. He attend attends the Stratford Ontario Shakespeare Festival from July 13-15, 1954 in Canada and speaks to various professionals in the arts.
    Theater; Turkey; Diaries; Dance; Ballet; Cultural studies; Egypt; England; Drama; Education; Music; Opera; Humanities; Lebanon
  - Trip to the Near East, March 16-April 4, 1954; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John (Reel M Mar 9, Frame 486, Box 300)
  - 1954 August 2-September 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 147 pages (Box 300, Reel M Mar 9, Frame 725)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts. Marshall travels to Canada, visits Harvard University and attends the Conference on the Future of Canadian-American Economic Relations at the University of Rochester.
    Diaries; Area studies; Cultural studies; Canada; Translations; United States; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Humanities; Middle East -- Study and teaching
  - Trip to Canada, September 19-30, 1954; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John (Reel M Mar 9, Frame 839, Box 300)
  - 1954 October 18-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 188 pages (Box 301, Reel M Mar 9, Frame 872)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The Humanities Program focus is to stimulate cultural growth by increasing aid to interpretative studies of recent studies, assist American studies in other countries, and grants in creative writing, music and the other arts. Marshall takes a trip to Los Angeles to visit various institutions involved in the arts and travels to Sarah Lawrence College.
    Opera; Diaries; Theater; United States; Education; Humanities; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Music; Drama
  - Trip to Los Angeles, December 11-31, 1954; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John (Reel M Mar 9, Frame 1,002, Box 301)
  - 1955 January 4-March 5, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 165 pages (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 1, Box 301)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall takes a trip to the Near East to survey Rockefeller Foundation opportunities and current political situations in the Middle East.
    Middle East -- Study and teaching; United States; Syria; Philosophy and religion; Music; Arts; Bibliography; Education; Egypt; Egyptology; England; Humanities; Iraq; Lebanon; Diaries; Libraries; Linguistics
  - Trip to Near East, January 25-March 5, 1955; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 9, Box 301)
  - 1955 March 5-May 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 213 pages (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 167, Box 301)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall's trip to the Near East continues in Lebanon and Turkey. In the United States, Marshall attends the Seventh Annual Near East Conference at Princeton University and takes a trip to Cambridge, Massachusetts to visit the Center for Middle Eastern Studies.
    Arts; Dance; Ballet; Drama; Humanities; France; Music; Lebanon; Theater; Opera; United States; Turkey; Diaries
  - 1955 June 2-September 23, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 179 pages (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 383, Box 301)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall attends the "Egypt, Pakistan and Turkey- An Islamic Renaissance" at the Harvard Summer School Conference, and the Kingston Conference/Canadian Writers Conference at Queens University in Canada.
    Canada; Arts; Humanities; Drama; Music; Diaries; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Theater; Opera; United States
  - 1955 September 23-1956 January 1, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 170 pages (Box 301, Reel M Mar 10, Frame 562)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall takes a travels to the West Coast; Cambridge, Massachusetts and the University of Michigan.
    Canada; Humanities; Drama; Music; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Theater; Poetry; United States; Arts; Diaries
  - Trip to the West Coast, September 23-October 9, 1955; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 563, Box 301)
  - 1956 January 3-March 9, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 161 pages (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 733, Box 302)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. The diary documents Marshall's interactions with the American Shakespeare Festival Theatre, Near East studies programs and the National Ballet of Canada.
    Theater; United States; Arts; Diaries; Ballet; Dance; Drama; Humanities; Middle East -- Study and teaching
  - 1956 March 10-May 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 206 pages (Box 302, Reel M Mar 10, Frame 894)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall takes a trip to the Near East from 10 March-16April 1956 to survey teaching English in Cairo and American studies abroad. In the United States, he takes a trip to Oak Ridge, Tennessee and gives his impressions and recommendations of the Oak Ridge Arts Council. Marshall also attends the ACLS Commission on the Humanities in Worchester, Massachusetts.
    Translations; Music; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Linguistics; Lebanon; Language and languages; United States; Diaries; Egypt; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Humanities; Iraq; Turkey; Arts; Education
  - Trip to the Near East, March 10-April 16, 1956; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 10, Frame 895, Box 302)
  - 1956 June 1-August 27, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 153 pages (Box 302, Reel M Mar 11, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall holds various conversations with Lincoln Kirstein regarding ballet, opera and the arts. He takes a trip to Massachusetts for the Jacob's Pillow Dance Festival at Lee, Massachusetts; and goes to Harvard University for the Conference on the Little Magazines, and Near East Studies program. In Canada, Marshal goes to the Pugwash Conference in Pugwash, Nova Scotia.
    Canada; Broadcasting; Dance; United States; Ballet; Arts; Music; Radio; Theater; Drama; Humanities; Diaries; Libraries; Middle East -- Study and teaching
  - 1956 August 28-December 28, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 163 pages (Reel M Mar 11, Frame 154, Box 302)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. This diary documents the various conferences that Marshall attended including the Middle East Research Program at Cambridge, Massachusetts; the Canada-United States Conference at the University of Rochester; Conference Meeting on Linguistics and the Teaching of English; Committee on International Exchange of Persons; Conference Board of the Associated Research Councils; and the Foreign Affairs Committee "People to People Program" at Princeton University.
    Diaries; Humanities; Language and languages; Drama; Music; Theater; Linguistics; United States; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Dance
  - 1957 January 3-March 31, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 234 pages (Reel M Mar 11, Frame 320, Box 302)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall takes a trip to the Near East from 1 March-31 March 1957. Topics that are discussed during this trip include philanthropy and the arts in Turkey, the Istanbul Conservatory, and teaching English in Egypt. The diary also details Marshall's conversations with Lincoln Kirstein regarding his impression of performing arts in the United States and Canada.
    England; Egypt; Humanities; France; Lebanon; Language and languages; Linguistics; Middle East -- Study and teaching; Music; Ballet; Arts; Dance; Cultural studies; Education; Diaries; United States; Turkey; Theater
  - Trip to Near East, March 1-31, 1957; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Mar 11, Frame 321, Box 302)
  - 1957 April 1-June 28, Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 121 pages (Box 303, Reel M Mar 11, Frame 554)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall visits Vanderbilt University to establish a relationship with the school and survey the humanities program. He holds a conversation with Harold Spivacke of the Library of Congress regarding non-Western music, and discusses the American Shakespeare Festival with Lincoln Kirstein.
    Middle East -- Study and teaching; Humanities; Education; Arts; Diaries; United States; Theater; Music
  - 1957 July 2-August 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 128 pages (Reel M Mar 11, Reel 675, Box 303)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects.
    Humanities; Music; Theater; United States; Diaries; Dance; Canada; Ballet; Arts
  - 1957 September 3-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 249 pages (Box 303, Reel M Mar 11, Frame 803)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall takes a trip to Europe from 17 November-31 December 1957.
    England; France; Germany; Diaries; Humanities; Netherlands; Switzerland; United States
  - Trip to Europe, November 17-December 31, 1957; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John (Box 303, Reel M Mar 11, Frame 804)
  - 1958 January 2-March 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 144 pages (Box 303, Reel M Mar 11, Frame 1,052)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall visits the State University of Iowa Playwright Conference.
    Diaries; Theater; Playwriting; United States; Arts; Drama; Humanities
  - 1958 April 2-June 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 114 pages (Reel M Mar 12, Frame 1, Box 304)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation's Humanities Division. The program is concerned with history, philosophy, linguistics and the arts. Grants are organized into intercultural studies, humanistic research, the arts and special projects. Marshall attends the Tenth Annual Conference on Near Eastern Studies at Princeton University, discusses a fire with Rene D'Harnoncourt and Arthur Drexler at Museum of Modern Art, and attends the ACLS Conference on the Discovery and Encouragement of Potential Humanistic Scholars.
    Dance; Museums; Humanities; Arts; Theater; Music; Diaries; United States
  - 1958 July 1-October 2, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; 98 pages (Box 304, Reel M Mar 12, Frame 115)
    Diaries; Humanities; United States; Arts
  - Trip to Europe, 5 October 1958 - 5 November 1958; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; 70 pages (Box 304, Reel M Mar 12, Frame 213)